<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chris Harris</title><link>https://cjharris.co.uk/</link><description>Recent content on Chris Harris</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cjharris.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cap - HackTheBox Machine Writeup</title><link>https://cjharris.co.uk/posts/cap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cjharris.co.uk/posts/cap/</guid><description>Difficulty: Easy
Operating System: Linux
Recon and Enumeration We will start this machine by doing a quick nmap, this will give an idea of what is running so that I can begin to tackle it.
nmap cap.htb
PORT STATE SERVICE 21/tcp open ftp 22/tcp open ssh 80/tcp open http After this, we can see 3 ports open:
An FTP server running on port 21. An SSH server running on port 22.</description></item><item><title>Advent of Code 2024 Solutions</title><link>https://cjharris.co.uk/posts/advent-of-code-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cjharris.co.uk/posts/advent-of-code-2024/</guid><description>For the 2024 Advent of Code challenge, I have published my developed solutions here.
All solutions are developed in Python3. The solutions created are the optimised solutions, I am planning on expanding on these with writeups soon.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://cjharris.co.uk/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:21:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cjharris.co.uk/about/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m cjharris (Chris), currently employed as a software developer and with a first class degree in Cyber Security. This blog aims to post content I find interesting or any independent research or labs that I feel I want to polish up and publish.
You can expect to see writeups for CTF challenges or HackTheBox machines, as well as any independent research I decide to undertake. I am particularly interested in malware analysis and digital forensics.</description></item><item><title>IntakeCTF - Missing Bytes Writeup</title><link>https://cjharris.co.uk/posts/intakectfmissingbytes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cjharris.co.uk/posts/intakectfmissingbytes/</guid><description>Here is my writeup for the Missing Bytes challenge from the IntakeCTF, hosted by the WMG Cyber Society. An internal CTF hosted at the University of Warwick for the Cyber Security students. I also posted this on their website.
We are told that the PNG image provided won&amp;rsquo;t open.
The first thing we can try is to use the pngcheck command, this will tell us if the PNG is corrupted, and if so hopefully how exactly it is corrupted.</description></item><item><title>Templated - HackTheBox Web Challenge Writeup</title><link>https://cjharris.co.uk/posts/templated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cjharris.co.uk/posts/templated/</guid><description>This writeup covers the steps taken to complete the Templated challenge in the Web category on HackTheBox. The challenge involved exploiting a Template Injection vulnerability to achieve Remote Code Execution (RCE) and ultimately retrieve the flag.
Upon starting the challenge, we are provided with the following:
Testing for Template Injection The first thing that stood out was the potential for a Jinja2 Template Injection vulnerability, which is common in web applications that render user input using Jinja2 templates.</description></item></channel></rss>